For the first time in my career, I made
a decision that didn't make any sense on
paper. Last year, I started a podcast to
practice speaking and shared the
software engineering career stories that
inspired me. Everything felt new and I
was learning a lot. After work, I kept
thinking about ways on how to make the
podcast better. I dreamed of working on
it full-time, but it never really made
sense because I'd only ever lost money
on it. Then late last year, there was a
reorg that felt like a good opportunity
to leave Meta early and try it out. So,
I decided to use six months of my
savings to see if I could make it work.
And at first, it was glorious. I
interviewed people like Bejarn Strost,
the creator of C++, who I'd looked up to
ever since I started learning C++ as my
first programming language. And it was a
lot of fun studying for every interview
and getting into video production. But
doing everything myself had an obvious
downside. If I stopped, everything
stopped.
I put so much time into each episode
that even though I was working more than
I ever had, I could barely keep up with
the goal of one episode per week. And
that's because I personally reviewed
every second of the footage and I did
deep research on each guest before the
interviews.
Well, four months into my six-month
runway, I still hadn't made a dollar,
and I'd been reluctant to monetize since
finding sponsors felt like time taken
away from the fun parts of creating
content.
But as my bank account got closer to
zero, I knew I couldn't put it off much
longer.
And then I got sick. I caught what felt
like a strong flu that had me bedridden
for a few days, lying there, drifting in
and out of consciousness. I remember I
kept wondering if I'd even be able to
publish an episode that Monday. And
because I couldn't work, suddenly
everything felt fragile for the first
time.
Thankfully, I had one episode already
mostly finished. So, that got me through
that week of sickness. And because of
that week, I finally started taking
sponsors seriously despite my
reluctance.
Also, I found ways to make my recording
process more efficient so I could do two
episodes a week to get ahead. Although
it was an insane grind. With some luck
and hard work, great sponsors like
Cursor and then Work OS, who I really
appreciate, signed on, which brought
some money in. And also, I cut my burn
rate a lot by recording every episode
myself. Aside from saving money, the
scrappiness of recording myself has been
a fun way to capture the essence of some
of my guests. For instance, the
interview with Bejorn was shot in his
own study against the wall of his C++
books with two iPhones.
I earmarked six months of money and it's
been nine months now. So, as you can
imagine, the podcast sustains itself.
And my other passion project, an
ergonomic keyboard that I wish existed,
raised the funds we needed within a day
of launching on Kickstarter.
If you want one, you can sign up on
Kickstarter still. I'll put a link in
the description.
My career decision didn't make sense on
paper then and to be honest it still
doesn't. For instance, I actually expect
the keyboard project to lose me money in
aggregate. But the goal with the podcast
and the keyboard wasn't to make money
otherwise I would have just stayed at
Meta.
I often think about how lucky I am to
get to work on my passion projects and I
just want to say thank you to everyone
who has supported my work along the way.
Without your support, the podcast would
have died and the keyboard would have
never seen the light of day. So, what's
next is I'm going to keep working on my
passion projects as long as I continue
to earn my keep. If you're curious about
the podcast, it's it's grown and I hope
that I can leverage that to bring on
better guests for you all in the future.
And if you want to see how it's going,
you can always check the top the top
podcast chart on Spotify. I'll put a
link in description. Usually, I struggle
to stay in the top 50, but I'm going to
keep pushing here. And so if you want to
help out, I'd greatly appreciate it if
you could drop a a rating for the
podcast on Spotify.
And then as for the keyboard, I've
actually been using the first sample off
the assembly line for the last two
weeks. Uh you could see it here. Here's
half of it, and here's the other half.
Um it's honestly a surreal feeling
seeing something that was just an idea.
it was abstract
uh become physical and it's it's
honestly exactly what I wanted. Um and
my next goal is to kind of bring this
into production at the highest possible
quality bar that I can. We're on track
to ship early next year and I'll put a
link in the description for the
newsletter for the keyboard if you want
to follow along.
So, as long as the podcast covers itself
and my living costs, I'm going to keep
pushing on these goals. And I hope that
what I produce is good enough that
you'll continue supporting it. And so,
if you want to follow along, you could
subscribe here. I'll put out occasional
updates along with all of the other
videos that I do make. So, thank you for
watching and once again I really
appreciate your support.